<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on Grace Ugochi Nneji</title>
    <link>https://graceugochinneji.github.io/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on Grace Ugochi Nneji</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://graceugochinneji.github.io/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course is an exploration of machine learning fundamentals and its application across various learning paradigms. It introduces key concepts and methods that drive modern intelligent systems, focusing on three primary types of learning: supervised learning, unsupervised learning, and reinforcement learning. 
        Topics covered may include: data preprocessing, feature selection, and model evaluation techniques; supervised learning methods such as linear regression, decision trees, and neural networks; unsupervised learning techniques including clustering, principal component analysis, and anomaly detection; and reinforcement learning fundamentals like Markov decision processes, policy gradients, and value-based learning. 
        Additionally, students will gain hands-on experience with machine learning tools and frameworks, working on real-world datasets through assignments and projects. By the end of this course, students will understand the essential machine learning algorithms, the situations in which each learning type is applicable, and how to evaluate and interpret the performance of these models, preparing them for further studies and applications in data science, AI, and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Foundations of Computing Systems with Practical Teaching of C Programming course provides a thorough understanding of how computers function at a fundamental level while offering hands-on experience in programming with C. The course combines theoretical and practical learning, where students explore the architecture and basic functions of computing systems and apply this knowledge in C programming sessions to reinforce how software interacts with hardware. Topics include CPU design, memory management, and input/output operations, providing essential insights into computer architecture. 
      C programming bridges the gap between theory and practice, enabling students to perform low-level operations like memory management, pointer manipulation, and bitwise operations. Practical coding sessions in C foster critical problem-solving skills as students implement algorithms, troubleshoot, and optimize code for hardware efficiency. Additionally, this foundation prepares students for careers in fields such as systems programming and embedded systems, where an understanding of both hardware and software is crucial. 
      To get started with C programming, students install Code::Blocks by downloading the `codeblocks-20.03mingw-setup.exe` from [https://www.codeblocks.org/downloads/binaries/](https://www.codeblocks.org/downloads/binaries/), and configure the MinGW compiler path within the software. They can then add this path to their system’s environment variables to enable easy access. After creating a new `.c` or `.cpp` file in Code::Blocks, students can write, compile, and execute their code, with the output and error messages displayed in the log for immediate feedback. 
      This comprehensive approach equips students with practical and theoretical knowledge essential for understanding computing systems and programming, setting a strong foundation for advanced computing studies and careers. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
        
    </item>

      <item>
      <title></title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Basic Communications and PC Networking course provides foundational knowledge and practical skills in networking concepts and Cisco configurations. Students explore network components such as routers, switches, and access points, learning how these elements facilitate communication across networks. 
        The course covers essential networking protocols, including TCP/IP, UDP, and ICMP, along with the fundamentals of IP addressing through IPv4 and IPv6, enabling students to understand and manage IP schemes, subnetting, and the advantages of IPv6’s expanded address space. 
        Through Cisco lab sessions, students gain hands-on experience in configuring and troubleshooting networks, using tools like Cisco Packet Tracer to practice setting up network devices, managing IP configurations, and implementing routing protocols. Security is also emphasized, with introductions to firewall configuration and access control lists to secure networks. 
        By the course's end, students are well-equipped to address real-world networking scenarios, preparing them for advanced studies or entry-level networking roles with a solid foundation in both theory and practical skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid></guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Introduction to Information Systems course provides a comprehensive foundation on how information systems support business operations, decision-making, and strategic planning. 
        This course examines the core components of information systems, including hardware, software, data, people, and processes, and explores how they integrate to collect, store, and process data effectively. 
        Students gain insight into the role of information systems in modern organizations, understanding how these systems enhance productivity, support managerial functions, and drive competitive advantage. 
        In addition to theoretical learning, students will engage in practical sessions using StarUML software for system design. 
        They will be introduced to essential modeling techniques such as Data Flow Context Diagrams, Use Case Diagrams and documentation, Sequence Diagrams, and Entity-Relationship Diagrams (ERD). 
        These practical components allow students to visualize and document system requirements, processes, and data interactions, enhancing their analytical skills in system design and information management. 
        By the end of the course, students will be equipped with a solid foundation in information systems and practical experience in system modeling, preparing them for further studies or roles in IT, business analysis, and management. &lt;/p&gt;</description>  
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
